

TRUONG THANH VAN

0907691543 | vantruong231095@gmail.com

District 5, Ho Chi Minh City

I aim to develop my skills and continuously learn to gain more hands-on experience in the purchasing field. I am committed to working with a high level of responsibility and efficiency, contributing my capabilities to support the company's sustainable growth. In the coming years, my goal is to advance to a managerial position and lead a team in managing a product category effectively.

Work Experiences

Central Retail in Vietnam

Jul 2024 - Present

Asisstant Category Manager - Cum Visual Merchandiser

- Assist in drafting the contract using the standard form based on the agreed terms with the supplier.
- Management and evaluation of product samles.
- Support product management, create/block codes, set purchase and selling prices in the system.
- Provide supports in populating data for reports on sales revenue, inventory status, and items with stock but no sales, based on the Buyer's reporting template.
- Support tracking sales performance of each product code and reporting to category manager to adjust the category.
- Support tracking sales, controlling prices and profits to optimize business profitability while delivering good value to consumers.
- · Research on new products and pricing strategies of competitors in the market.
- Work with suppliers to resolve issues related to product expiration dates.

Central Retail in Vietnam May 2022 - Jun 2024

Visual Merchandiser - FMCG & Fresh

- · Review and allocate product category positions on the store layout.
- · Arrange shelves and fixtures for each product category.
- Create and manage the category's planogram allocate positions for hanging banners and hangers within the category.
- · Guide and hand over necessary preparations to the supermarket's category team leaders for new store openings.
- · Coordinate with related departments (Project, Demand Planning, Merchandise, etc.) to ensure smooth operations.

Red Circle Company Limited

Feb 2019 - Feb 2022

Store Manager

- Place periodic orders based on sales velocity and actual inventory to ensure adequate supply is always available.
- Monitor and check product expiry date; rotate goods according to FIFO principle to minimize waste.
- Displaying goods according to image standards (planogram), increasing aesthetics and attracting customers.
- Analyze customer traffic near the store to make appropriate ordering decisions, minimizing risks such as out-of-stock or near-expiry
 products. Monitor market trends and take responsibility for store sales performance; assess market conditions to help increase company
 revenue.
- Prepare weekly/monthly sales reports for managementCoordinate with relevant departments (Data, Accounting, etc.) to ensure smooth operations.
- Employee management and timekeeping

Education Level

Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology - Ho Chi Minh City

Oct 2014 - May 2017

Bachelor of College of Hotel and Restaurant Management Practice

Certificate

Microsoft Office Specialist Excel 2019 Associate by IIG

Relevant Skills

- Foreign Languages: Basic English communication skills.
- Office Computer: MS Excel, MS PowerPoint, MS Word.
- Working Under Pressure: Schedule and allocate time to task.
- · Communication: Work closely with relevant departments to ensure the company operates efficiently.